all right hello YouTube all I believe it
is on I know it is public because idea
cafe right this is the one that's public
sorry and so many conversations every
week today's question we are all
discussing is what is a game be project
that I we want to support in 2020
surrendering it for ourselves
I'm gonna answer it for Brent here is
gonna script for me great project I want
Brent to support it's funny so everyone
has up to five minutes to share does
that say we go that long and but I will
cut you off at the five minute mark if
you go to that point and we if you want
to pass you're more than welcome to pass
and just have a be part of the
conversation at the end we all the other
idea cafes are limited to half an hour
but gain you can't possibly be living in
a half an hour so we live in it to an
hour which even then we sometimes go
Eric that is highly triggering for me
today as it's been on my mind a lot I
plugged it in cuz I started to hear an
echo it didn't actually put it on like
why did Eric get so quiet all of a
sudden okay I think your your mic
Jubilee is is kanarchy yeah I can hear
you I think it's just the same computer
mic though like you have to switch in
the program to make it
pick up your headset mic now you muses
[Laughter]
thank you is that better
can you hear through this mic can hear
you clearly but I don't know if it's
picking up in that mic or not well I tap
on it does it sound like I'm tapping on
it no no I don't know if this has ever
worked then that's what I'm thinking
luckily I just ordered a new one
the issue is with Eric once Arick joins
I hear maybe though having it plugged in
is better because then I hear without
the echo and then if it sounds ok to
everyone else well I'll leave it like
this ok who would like to start sharing
on what gave me project they would like
to support in 2020 I've got a fairly
radical proposal is not really a
particular project like sport but I'd
like to put an idea out there and see
see if there's any any any any
enthusiasm for it I have actually
mentioned it before namely to use a
Jubilee you know use that Jubilee weapon
not not you Jubilee but the Jubilee do
you all know what the Jubilee is do you
know what I'm talking about no ok
I'll very very briefly explaining things
it won't take me long I'm not my idea is
really simple but the idea that the
Jubilee is essential to understand so
basically it's an undertaking that
people make anonymously until such time
as a threshold number is reached once a
certain number of people have made that
commitment then it is opened up it
becomes transparent and open to
everybody and so it can be used for
anything what it does is it negates the
thing of well well there's no point in
me doing it on my own because that makes
no difference right in all that happens
as they throw me in jail if I do it on
my own where a million people through it
that's not the case anymore right so
it's like a safety in numbers thing is
is the idea of it leverages it leverages
the public's power so anyway I would
like to use and I'm happy to talk more
about it afterwards I don't want to go
through long in this bit but I would
like to use it to try and put an end to
standardized testing in state education
well in all education actually a bit
state education see that's what educates
most children and you know it's not just
the testing itself it's everything that
goes around the testing the creation of
curriculums around the test schools
being measured by their test results
teachers being paid by their tested bla
bla bla bla bla bla bla all the shit
that goes along with it
so I think the Jubilee it would be it
would be a really good thing to use it
on because it's not too explosive it's
not like bringing down the economic
system right it's not it's not that kind
of and so it could be a test run for the
concept as well as being an opportunity
to put an
into this incredibly poisonous thing
that exists in our society and and I'll
stop there all right would anyone else
like to go now and even pause I didn't
even mute us I'm pretty good at not
interrupting each other now you know our
branch or I can go as well I can go so
what game B projects am i interested in
one of the things Jordan Hall mentioned
you know that he and John for Vicki are
having this conversation about a
religion that's not a religion of you
know wisdom the development of a wasting
tradition and I that is if nothing else
I that is those are conversations that I
would love to be a fly on the wall in
and like you know I hope that all of
them are streamed on YouTube or like I
can be a fly on the wall in those
conversations just because there is so
much there and for me this morning I
shared a post in the game beep it's a
group about you know my experience and
somebody commented on it and you know
was talking about the being in that
liminal space and one of the things that
I do in my day-to-day life is that there
are people who I'm helping who are
walking through that space walking
through the oh shit the world is not
what I think it is and I have do I do
life differently scuse me for my
language and you know there and it's you
know for me it was an extremely painful
long drawn-out process and so I want to
help figure out ways to make that
process not necessary you know there is
an inevitable amount of pain that comes
from that process but how to help people
not have to necessarily experience the
amount and time the the amount in time
of pain that I did just because I didn't
have anybody to reach out to and ask for
help and say because I didn't know what
was going on I didn't know what I was
experiencing and so being there
available for people as a resource
creating resources for people to come to
when they realize oh shit I've got to
change everything about my life and I've
got to you know do all of these things
and I don't know what I don't know how
how to even begin or how to start so
that's that is then the trajectory and
direction of my life for the last couple
of years and so I don't know what that's
going to look like or how it's going to
manifest but a couple years ago Jordan
Jordan Hall posted an article and I said
the part I'm interested in is the most
is the emotional triage that comes from
the realization that oshit life isn't
what I think it is and because there is
a massive amount of stuff to work
through and you know how do you and like
and in the conversation I was having
with you know a couple weeks ago it's
like my journey was part of my journey
with coming off of psych meds that
basically took several years where I
just need a and I didn't have like as
much or as I think people need and it
basically I needed good things to just
like not deal with life for an extended
couple of years and sort of like cocoon
while I dealt with all of the emotional
stuff and so how to create an
environment where that's possible I
don't know exactly how to do that but
that's what I'm interested in doing
Oh Bradford you want me to go I'll give
it a try I'm not very prepared today and
this is a tough question right like what
what game B projects do we want to
support like there's thousands and
thousands of nonprofits and projects
that are asking for support that deserve
support and you know someone like me
doesn't have anything to give except my
time and I already give all my time to
what you know whatever project so so
there's this kind of like you know
stagnation and kind of paralysis like
what what do we do and um you know a lot
of a lot of charities and a lot of
philanthropy is like like if you support
them you're not necessarily helping game
be you might be helping gate may write a
lot of charities and philanthropies are
corrupt or dysfunctional or even
best-case scenario they just they just
don't work or they don't change the
system they just try to address a kind
of externality that no one else is
dealing with um so in terms of whatever
what am I gonna focus on in 2020 it's
you know my own work a lot of meta stuff
Bernie Sanders movements and and I say
movement and campaign um because it's
all these things it takes us all of us
converging and a lot of these projects
merging there's one there's one like
kind of project that that pops into my
head though as something I do want to be
involved with but it you know it's to be
yet to be seen if it's yet another just
kind of you know front or well
intentioned attempt or if it's actually
it couldn't make it impact and that's uh
Robert Downey jr. is footprint Cole
and just listen to him talk about it is
pretty inspiring because he directly you
know takes a lot of his ideas from kind
of being Iron Man for for ten plus years
and uh you know like Brett rather than
that being just like a like a mmm
egocentric actor thing or a publicity
stunt like he's he's pretty serious
about it
and I think I think there is a kind of
ethics and methodology to the the role
that he played in in the Marvel
Cinematic Universe like specifically
wanting to you know dismantle the
military-industrial complex like that's
that's kind of what Tony's Arc is about
so you know Robert Downey jr. as a
person like Eaton he knows that he's not
actually Tony Stark and that's a
superhero but he wants to step into this
into this role I'll do what he can
because he understands the stakes and
kind of like bit that were we're talking
about a massive transition not just some
band-aid solution to a particular social
or ecological issue so yeah though those
things are all what I really wanted to
say just I'm gonna keep working on the
on the big picture on my research and on
the socio-political movement the EDS
that dovetail with that thanks Brett
focusing on in 2020 I have my own
project Jubilee project that's not that
table iam project on creating the global
cooperative but being in the game be
space I'm also learning how much of what
I have already done has to be thrown
away so that we can create it together
and having the frustration of being in a
space the old personnel's frustration of
being in a space where we all have our
own projects but how do any of them get
made or even ones that are very similar
how do we choose between them or how do
we melt them
together and how do way so for 2020 what
I would like to do personally and with
other game B people is one of two things
or potentially both which is create a
tool a very simple tool for
conversations because this is the most
powerful part of both like creating a
project doing the interpersonal work of
not going through it show up self
development and all of that time and and
uncomfortableness or pain that goes
through the progression you need to go
through and conversation and community
makes it easier especially when you
don't need to put in a lot of the effort
to find that community and those
conversations I just posted on the
Facebook group for a request for a
question like I want to talk to people
at decentralization and why that scene
is the end-all be-all of tools for a
technology like why is that what we're
concentrating on and I want to have that
conversation not necessarily for the
game be space but like for my learning
because I keep getting from lack of a
better word triggered when I hear
decentralization in the space because
I'm like what like you're not the thing
they're talking about generally isn't
fixes decentralization in my opinion and
so it's about going anyway
I want to be able to have conversations
I'm already doing that myself I'm doing
that throughout the week and the idea
cafe but I want to be able to create a
platform that makes it easy for anyone
to be able to schedule any conversation
they want to have with other people
because I think that's one of the best
ways to grow one of the other the other
projects that's one is figuring out how
to have a conversation under a
collaboration platform I guess no
conversation platform the other one is
what I think of as a collaboration
platform it may be that's not what it
comes out to be is that since everyone
has their own project since everyone has
their own thing that they're doing
whether that's the personal work whether
that's their own real life project or
online project that to bring those
people together with their unique
individual selves and their needs and
their projects needs and their projects
pitfalls and and you know um potential
how can we help one another right now in
this space right what is what is
stopping your individual project and how
can we facilitate each other how do we
help distribute trust amongst us right
so that if you have a new
for a project and it's created if we
have a way to back each other's projects
in trust or so than in finances to say
wait do we trust it and how do we trust
it which seems to be one of those magic
things that decentralization somehow
just solves without actually solving it
is that so bringing people together to
have like a meta project on how we
actually help each other's projects and
what can you create is it any of ours
but is all of ours that helps facilitate
the individual ones as well as a tool
for conversation just like what you want
to talk about schedules it with people
from different time zones and puts you
on a screen with for people not
necessarily broadcast on YouTube just
for your own personal growth and it's
learning and you can happen on and you
know if you see how other people have a
conversation that you're not available
for you could say hey I still want to be
part of a conversation like that but my
time doesn't line up or that spots
already full who else is available and
can make it for game people but it can
be for a broader audience as well so
that is what I will be concentrating on
in 2020 I like the notion of a communal
space where a conversation that needs to
be had that's a place where it can be
had right and so people can organize
around that space I think there's a
couple of things came up while you were
talking the decentralization thing I
mean in a way what you are doing the
project you're talking about facilitates
exactly that right it allows things to
come about spontaneously without any
kind of external direction that's what
decentralization is all about right so
you don't have an authority whatever it
might be
King em for a government think tank
whatever it doesn't matter but there is
not an authority figuring out what the
best plan is and then distributing it to
everyone right that's that that's that's
that centralization so what you were
advocating with your whole your whole
speech basically is a is a plea for
decentralization right for distributed
for distributed networks of sense-making
that's that's exactly what you're
advocating for so I think that to me
anyway that's what that's what
decentralization means Kira sorry I'm
just going to bury
quickly go in a circle and then I'll
shut up but here are your desire to
create like a halfway house sort of
thing for people that are coming through
their awakening or whatever whatever it
is you want to call it this - yeah I
mean language is so difficult
hi everyone brings different things but
anyway wait I think I know what you're
talking about
the I don't know if you saw it a few
weeks ago I did this Messer wrote this
meta print thing which I put up on the
game B page and a few people have kind
of yeah different people a girl called
Carolyn has got in touch with me
recently Luke McBain and Heather watts
and there are a couple and Wendy as well
there's there's something forming around
this I think you would like it I think
it's yes it's along the lines of what
you want to do it's it's it's about it's
exactly the same spirit behind the
project that Jon vivace and Jordan Hall
have been talking about you know this
this this secular wisdom tradition you
know creating a new wisdom traditions
exactly or it centers around so I mean
if you if you'd like to be a part of
these conversations when they when they
get going again I mean that'd be great
the more the merrier yeah I thought so
and Brent there was something so I
wanted oh yeah yeah yeah Robert Downey
jr. footprinting I haven't heard
anything about it but I really like him
I think he's a really genuine guy all of
this you know Bluff arrogance think it's
just a front it's just to be funny I
think these are really really genuine
guy so I'd be interested to know more
about this I've not heard about I'd be
interested to know more about it the one
of the questions that came to - did you
look into the post that Jordan into the
Facebook group I think it was Friday
where there's a group over in the case
and we're looking for researchers mmm
it's also not what I'm looking to do
yeah that's the part that I found
interesting about that was just the the
structure of the of the quite of like
having one question that was driving
everything
and what are the you know it sort of as
a place of where to hook into you know
the metaphor the metaphor how do you
represent all of the things that people
are looking you know that people are
working on so that you know you don't
end up with ten trees that are all doing
different things and nobody's talking to
each other and how do you how do you
solve that particular problem and again
that one seemed more centralized than
you know then what you're necessarily
looking to do but that's an interesting
part of that quote question how do you
solve that particular piece of yeah
creating the of bringing people together
who are talking about things in wonder
one area and another like I I like that
these these videos are broadcast and
then people can you know find it you
know that they they might find something
interesting and reach out to that person
and you know then you get people
connected but yeah how do you how do you
create that opportunity for connections
I really liked the structure and that's
I guess what I mean by did not turn this
into the decentralization conversation
because I put that on Facebook too how
that is a unique one but like that
project is amazing I don't see it
essential in east-central I see them as
having solved a problem using the best
tool they have under their disposal
right this idea of branch internals new
apparent turtle and child turtle but
there's no hierarchy like it solves the
problem without making it too
centralized right it's centralized
actually and so that's the issue of like
like listening to the forest laundry
thing this morning where they were
talking about like Facebook's broken
because it's not decentralized so we
need the central and I'm like wait no
Facebook's broken because it has a
for-profit model and it's game a if it
if we all owned it and we can decide
what tools to add to it it would be an
amazingly powerful tool and the
centralization would make it more
powerful not less so but that's but by
definition that's decentralized if it's
owned by all of us by definition it is
deed that is that is decentralization
right that is distribution of ownership
those decentralization of ownership so
yeah I think I think it's actually think
your issue with centralization
semantics one I think it's what you
bring to the word is is the thing yeah
when I describe what I'm doing I'm like
a technology company we all own together
so can create the tools to solve our
problems who were like no that sounds
like centralized Asia and I'm like do
you listen to Facebook does Facebook
dictate your life do you know they have
a real powerful control over your life
but I'm not listening to the mother I
have kids with who devotes like maybe
I'm listening for base for their
algorithm we can do that together so
it's much more transparent and like we
would make its you vote for one person
because we wouldn't have enough people
to want to be like Bernie Sanders is the
one we all would want truth in politics
which means Bernie Sanders might come up
as the frontrunner based on truth and
what we actually want with you know what
I mean like without pursing an ideology
and that's where like it's just this
like disagreement that's not really a
disagreement which is why I want to have
this conversation and I'm getting fairly
good at like whatever pretty good up to
the University like this conversation
here's the time period people show up
but they don't show up but I'm fairly
far along in that and other people
aren't and other people see people
having conversations and they it's
vulnerable to put yourself out there and
want to have that and then not be able
to have people respond to it right so
having a tool that just makes this
process easy if it's just like wait what
kind of conversations do we want to have
and how do we just as simple to oh like
how do you get people to conversation
around the topic or a question that they
want to participate in what does that
tool look like that we all can create
together or not because if I create the
idea cafe it's for me write it like it
solves my need of like I like each
taking five minutes and then having a
conversation at the end it's a very
formatted unformatted for me but doesn't
make it fit everybody so like getting
people together to have the conversation
about what does that tool look like
maybe nobody else in the game bSpace has
this problem than I do in which case I'm
solving a problem only for me and
therefore won't be solves but that like
just getting people to a conversation
and making it much easier I think one of
the one of the interesting parts of this
is you know I think there are people who
are
I've heard I've heard this talked about
in other places of their people who are
living the game be who are living game
be but don't identify identify as game
be and the and yeah there's a lot of
them and there are so and I and I know
quite a few people in the you know
personal coaching hippie space I'll just
call it that and you know I see them you
know conversations popping up in terms
of you know that the in that case it's a
lot more of the emotional work that's
being done to move through you know the
to transition from you know kind of game
a mentality to game be mentality and
there's a but there's and and I guess
there's there's an element of how do we
how do you how do we put this game a let
game be language on you I'm not on to
that's not the right word that's not
exactly the right word but how do we if
the the conversations that we're having
and sort of bringing attention to places
where that where people are already
living that game beef you know where
they're living game be but they're not
using that language yeah and I mean and
and I don't even like necessarily the
process of you know calling it something
because then you know it's kind of like
it you know the tower that you name is
not that's you know that's that type of
thing it's like once you name it it sort
of like well is it that or is it not
that it's that whole and it's also in
group out through then right isn't it
yeah yeah we're getting you're not game
be you know yeah it does I'm interested
because I'm also in some of those spaces
like and it's interesting because all of
the different types of group seem to
form around one or two thought leaders
whether that's spiritual because they
can channel other things or their
self-help guru or their you know Jordan
Hall or like whatever it happens to be
and so it's alright when we have that I
think it's harder to be more universal
because we're putting that somewhat of
the higher like the power on a hierarchy
right that these people are the ones who
are disseminating our knowledge to the
rest of us and then we were banding
together as an us-versus-them in some
degree with them as like right because
we all agree with what Jordan Hall says
right even if we don't agree with Jordan
Hall says it becomes almost like
entry-level that you have to agree with
him and which I do have yet to hear
Jordan of all say something that I don't
agree with I can't say is actually true
for the other people that I follow
there's always something that I disagree
with and having that like a piece of it
is kind of like breaking down the
hierarchy of external versus internal
knowledge in all the spaces right if
what Jordans make sense to you then it
becomes your truth and you're speaking
from your your truth not his yeah and it
from teal Swan and and Kyle sees who are
the other ones that that I follow and
have more of a a group around that it's
like if what she says resonates with you
go for it but don't call someone
teal when you say that you know like
Jordan Hall would agree with that right
I'm not talking Hall Jordan halls don't
all he does an amazing job at it but no
one else needs to be him we need to be
ourselves which is like a combination of
all of the information but it's also
group making to have these people that
we all know right that are like weekend
sorry care but just really quickly you
can make it very good we were already a
group right and what brought us here was
that he articulated things in a way that
you know what I mean and so we were
already that group we just hadn't formed
yet if you see what I mean does that
does that make sense yes is that so the
group hasn't been created by simply been
attracted to they were already in
existence in some unformed way does that
make sense yeah I think you're talking
about the you know the be God what's the
Terminator Roy is is like self organize
you know self organizing
yeah yeah the emerging and
self-organizing black Isis yeah the the
thing that was coming up for me is you
know one of the interesting things is I
don't have a lot of fear when it comes
to reaching out to random people online
and asking them questions but I know
that that's not something that everyone
has the confidence of and I had you know
and I and you know I took I reached out
to Jordan and said hey are you willing
to have a conversation with me and he
did and like having that conversation
that like it allowed me to have I don't
like I it it took what what I saw as
like something I I couldn't express like
having that conversation gave me the
courage to be able to express myself in
more openly in the group and not to say
that that's what everyone should be
doing but it's you know how do we you
know how do we encourage people to be
able to express their voices in in
groups like this because I think one of
the problems is not everybody's gonna
feel confident hopping on it on a group
call that's gonna be broadcast on
YouTube or even just on a group call
period like wait a minute what if these
people might think I'm stupid or you
know what a you know or whatever I have
you know from whatever I have to say and
so how to you know kind of help people
move through that and again I always
tend to come back to you know the
emotional stuff and moving through the
fears and I'll you know that's that's my
area that I like but how to how to
empower people you know to feel like
they had that their voice is an
important part of the conversation and
remember in one of I think I might have
mentioned this last week that and one of
the Congress in the conversation between
Jordan and Denver Vicki they talked
about you know like maybe the
information that's needed is from a
seven-year-old girl in Peru like but how
do you you know how do you empower
that voice and but then it's but then
there's that balance of between
empowering somebody to want to speak and
then oh wait I have a voice I'm going to
project it everywhere and I have to say
and where's that line yeah and I think
that is a very important line because
this idea that it could come from a
seven nine year old girl in Peru is huge
it absolutely could you know why'd it
probably will oh right the issue is
there's as someone who thinks I do have
a solution but I can't quite articulate
it and I can't quite it's like the
systems aren't designed it's like well
if you can't communicate it well I exist
like right but that is a sticking point
like it's like but it exists in my head
like it's where is the process to go
through to say is this good is this not
what can we try what can't we try
because the barriers of entry it's like
it has to be something has to come
through to somebody who has enough power
and privilege to be able to get it out
into the world the change they have to
be able to communicate it to the masses
and therefore we amplify voices that
have better editing and sound better
instead of like the quality of the
actual idea right the quality of like
wait what did that proofing girl say and
is there gold there and there has to be
in a way where it's not this top-down
structure we're all listening to these
leaders and instead we're listening to
each other and saying yes what is that
there's something of gold there right
there's something and things will still
fall through the cracks but less so when
we say if we truly believe it can come
from anyone we have to listen to
everyone right and we have to find like
play ovo mega role and find the like
signal in the noise even when it's
mostly no audience that's not what
went away Brent you go anything um not
really
I like what well in that case tell me a
little bit more about Robert Downey jr.
just just quickly about two minutes
worth tell me a little bit more bad yeah
like I wish I did a refresher before I
came on here mm-hmm
because I didn't like all the military
industrial complex
I mean that's that's more my
extrapolation I think more generally
it's just thing something like climate
change you know exactly right that's
what we need another yet another climate
change solution but yeah I mean he's
just taken a different approach and
using his resources and networks and
like I don't I don't know what what what
involvement with by someone like me
would look like like I'm on like the
waiting list or whatever you know for
updates but I basically watched him
unpack it twice once in a Howard Stern
interview there's like a short clip of
him talking about it and once on on a
stage mmm
introducing some event right he just
came out there and you know kind of kind
of whips up the crowd and it's basically
like I think you know justjust he wants
to build a coalition right like more
more organizations converging on the
solution and it is a solving climate
change is not a technical problem like
that's his kind of Catalina you know
inciting incident like he's like why
aren't we doing it right if we can't so
he's trying to you know throw his weight
towards you know collaborating on a
global scale to make that happen
you know action on climate change and
you know all the all the Avengers so to
speak like I aggressively reality and
that's inspiring to me like Mark Ruffalo
is a Bernie surrogate he's very active
on the campaign trail with with Bernie
in his own way and Chris Evans Captain
America is like super progressive and
super you know I don't want to say
opinionated on Twitter because I think
he's right but you know he's just a kind
of a a moral anchor in a sense you know
and and so you know all of these guys
like are superstars but they're also
down-to-earth mm-hmm and I think they
try to you know fill the the characters
shoes that they play in real life as
much as possible so yeah I mean that
that's the thing that's the thematic
thing that I'm trying to express well I
could just have really good PR guys as
well right of course
yeah yeah yeah it's it's working on me a
genuine interesting sorry
so he could Jubilee go ahead you go
ahead I just just but I did want to
mention what Kira had mentioned before
which is um like how do we make people
comfortable I guess enough in this space
that they feel like they can show up and
get it wrong my gut feeling is that we
do that by showing you can get it wrong
like we get it wrong on repeat we create
a culture that allows for mistakes and
allows for people to do all of the
practice that is necessary to get it
wrong on the path to getting it right
right mess up on the Omega rule
constantly while trying to get it right
look get the
explain back to me what I just said so
that we can see if we're in the same
understanding even if it's wrong it's
getting us closer together than it being
right and not needing people to have a
degree in our linguistics to be able to
have a conversation and the more we
allow that to happen I think the more
allowing error it's encouraging error
I mean errors good error reveals error
teachers you know what I mean I wish I
saw a great documentary a few years back
called beings and change billionaire
sort of invested all his money and in
building this technology part to try and
solve you know water energy the really
really big problems of the world is a
really really cool guy but one of his
mattress is quick to fail if the thing
is gonna fail let's find out quickly
right so push it hard push it early and
if it's gonna fail then let's know
quickly and let's move on to something
else right not spend a long time on
something that's eventually gonna fail
right quick to failure are there and so
you know these these ideas are really
important it's the opposite of what we
learn in school right this broadcast
thing you know getting the question
right is is what we're trained to do
right getting it wrong is no no that's a
Red Cross and that's an author out of 10
and that's Addie and all that kind of
shit right so getting stuff wrong is
very very I mean there's another thing
of the standardized testing right this
this whole mentality if it's right or
it's wrong and you're good or you're bad
or you're an A or you're an e or
whatever this whole fucking thing is an
absolute horror and so yeah sorry I'm
not actually trying to standardize
character well in there inherent in that
is making it that you know doing away
with the idea that failure is a bad
thing you know they're not there's a
there there's this concept of there is
no failure only feedback exactly that
comes from neuro linguistic programming
I love it
yeah and that's that's one that's like
okay you know cuz like and it's funny
the a few minutes ago there was
something that I was going to say
and I didn't want to say it because I
was afraid of being laughed at and you
know that's you know well stow I and so
I'm gonna say it because I'm scared too
and so you guys know that I'm afraid to
be that I'm gonna be laughed at even if
you do it's not gonna kill me
there was so back in the early 90s there
was a book that came out I think is
really nineties called The Celestine
Prophecy I'd never ever heard I'm sure
you've heard of it and I had never read
it and recently somebody suggested that
I read it and so I did and to me there
is something you know now that I
understand kind of like the mythopoetic
ideas it's a very melodic idea of kind
of describing sort of the things that
are emerging from from game be you know
if you take it literally then it's kind
of silly but if you take it you know as
a metaphor for what's happening it makes
total sense of like okay if there's
somebody who's if like one of the things
and it was you know if you know if you
catch someone's eye and you like you
know see each other maybe there's
something there to that you have to
learn from each other and you know kind
of the same thing and how do you enable
that when you don't see each other's
faces so much online it's like oh
there's that interesting conversation
and create it create a safety of if I
say something interesting and you don't
want to share about it publicly
reach out to me into it you know reach
out to me individually because there's
probably something like I've learned to
trust that voice in my head that says
you need to talk to that person you know
you you should you should you know join
that conversation but not everybody does
that and so how do we encourage that and
and and how do we encourage like you
know cuz some of the stuff that I have
it's like I haven't I have that voice in
my head that says that's dumb or people
are gonna laugh and you know and maybe
maybe is but you never know so you put
it out there and you know maybe it is
just saying hey I have this this thing
and I'm afraid you're gonna laugh
that will create sense of safety that
it's like okay if I preface that and
usually people aren't gonna laugh you
know usually people won't laugh if you
say that it's like this is me being
Google you know how do we how do we
model that it's okay to be vulnerable
and especially for a game be space game
be specifically seems like it's very
much a group of very intelligent people
who are very good at talking about ideas
and when you have that it's like wait a
minute
sometimes our idea can you know we can
conflate our ideas with who we are and
if you if you're if you don't like my
idea then you don't like me and like
separating those things out and and
creating you know it's like I adore the
concept of safe spaces and we don't want
to create safe space but do you want to
yeah make it okay to fail okay Nick
mistakes I think that's ultimately what
people want when they talk about safe
spaces is they want to know that there's
some place that they can go and like not
be ridiculed for making a mistake
listen yeah thanks for like what was
coming up for me when you were talking
is like we moved from this very home the
course of generations from a very tribal
world where like if you thought outside
of the box you got ostracized and the
Internet has given us the ability to
like form our own tribes and do but it's
also given us this mega tribe that like
you do something wrong you get
eviscerated and there's nowhere else to
go right you're on Twitter and you say
something slightly racist or wholly
racist right but like if you had said it
at a party and gotten it wrong and like
got the feedback of like that's highly
racist and no it wouldn't you know I
mean it has more of a projection so it
has more of a consequence and like
making it so that honestly it's a safe
space to even say things that you aren't
allowed to say online which is kind of
what the safe space movement has done is
like you can't say anything so
everyone's watching everything they're
say and none of us are actually growing
and progressing if you're following
those rules and so creating small
microbe spaces that are like listen this
isn't which is a little weird that's on
YouTube or it could you don't everything
it could go viral
yeah but like we can have a culture that
allows the mistake make sense like game
be to say like listen I'm gonna give you
the benefit of the doubt and not think
you're a racist homophobic transphobic
asshole because of something you said on
Twitter I'm going to you know have a
conversation with you about it or assume
that even if that's true there's
underlining goodness there that we can
concentrate on well hopefully you grow
through whatever the surface level anger
fear certain like creating micro safe
spaces that aren't about PC but are
about you're allowed to make a mistake
and we're still your bill still be a
space for you as soon as you said that I
have this notebook that's right next to
me which is my notes from John Verbeck
e-series and that one of the the things
that's in the right in the middle of the
page is when we got rid of Christianity
we got rid of the metaphysics of cosmic
Redemption there it that that is there
in the PC culture there is no space for
redemption and how do we you know how do
we bring that back of you made a mistake
you are not excommunicated from the
tribe you know we're not you you are not
which you know when you're
excommunicated from the tribe in in this
day and age it's I'm not loved you know
it can trigger whatever your deep you
know I'm I'm not loved
I'm not acceptable you know whatever it
whatever your deep wounding is because
we all got different one no they come
down to a few core ones but that there
is space for redemption and bringing in
and I'ma and and there's something about
that specific language to me that is
it's you know that extending the idea
that everyone has something that
everyone is redeemable and yeah if if
somebody's wrong about something though
like in order to be redeemed they have
to learn
their lesson and realize what they were
wrong about and what the right answer or
what a better answer is and we don't we
don't see that very often so what I'm
hearing is like there's this compassion
in a good sense to like like like let
people make mistakes and keep keep them
in the conversation but this is it's
it's very challenging and problematic
for me because there's so many bad ideas
that get smuggled in and we might do it
ourselves we might smuggle in some Dogma
and not know it so we need ways to mmm
you know call out or call in each other
and and correct that information um but
but did this idea of like redemption or
something like it like it's it comes it
only comes after the the person has sort
of done something different to earn that
Redemption right they it's it's a verb
like to redeem yourself
and so uh I'll just I'll draw from one
example because it's because it's fresh
in my mind
actually um somebody posted in in the in
the Facebook group the other day mmm
like what are some book recommendations
you know I've read they suggested to I
forget one but the other was a book by
David Brooks and I just made a like a
short kind of dismissive comment I
wasn't trying to be rude to the person
but kind of just dismissive to David
Brooks I said David Brooks like was you
know for the Iraq war and you know I I
don't think ever really II you know
deeply learned his mistakes like he's
still a pretty centrist person you know
and so he gets criticized a ton from the
left so there's just this needed context
right when we when we parsed this new
information so I looked at his book
which is it's a recent book and it
kind of autobiographical and it's like
it's decent but it's you know it I think
David Brooks is still fundamentally
somebody who deserves critique and and
and like I did eventually share like ten
articles critiquing David Brooks like
look here here it is so you know when we
talk about making mistakes like are we
talking about like so the person who who
shared that was like you know
appreciative that we had some new
information but you know are we talking
about forgiving david brooks because
he's making his best effort like is he
actually helping the cause you know i
don't know what did david brooks do you
might have just said oh he's the new
york times columnist that's that that's
his thing and he's kind of a kind of a
centrist uh
and and he you know the specific example
i'm using his he supported the Iraq war
which of course in retrospect was just a
terrible idea but lots of people at the
time were against it and he was somebody
who was for it you know based on the
information that he thought he had uh
and but it but it's just generally you
know the thing things people hate about
him is in the discourse you know he he
presents himself as this prevent / very
professional very considered thinker you
know and and more critical people just
see through that like oh he's just an
apologist for empire at worst right so
you know there's a paradox here and how
we you know try to bring people into the
conversation with compassion and let
that let their let their ideas you know
be expressed but then when we're talking
about building complex systems and and
new ideologies like it's a very
sensitive process it's it's a very
collective project like we have to kind
of be critical of each other but in a
compassionate way
so I is not good simply won't gain
traction right so people can express
their odor isn't there shit ideas they
just weren't getting any traction they
won't go any further right though
they'll be heard in that moment yeah I
wish self-regulating at least in theory
hopefully with some intelligent people
it would be but I think maybe is that
space I don't like the idea that you
have to change your behavior before you
get Redemption can I just pick up on
that because III think grant makes a
really valid point there I don't think
you can be redeemed unless you recognize
the mistake that you've made right I
want to make a suggestion because like a
child or when you like I have autism and
so I have met I have breakdowns I got
like there's I can't promise that's not
gonna happen again my point is is it in
the moment I make a mistake I can't
promise it's not gonna happen again
there's no changing to do there but to
save the to sit in the shame of oh I
said something wrong or I acted in a way
that they thought was impolite or
whatever it happens to be the redemption
part because this is my issue with a lot
of things is that these new cultures
like yelling at children to apologize to
each other you hit your brother
apologize it's not an actual change it's
not an actual and so if you first
require the change in behavior as
opposed to how do we love you where you
are which is to me the only key to
redemption is to truly love like that
underlining piece right they may be a
misogynistic asshole Welcome Table but
if we can see the humanity and that's
part of the humanity underneath you
don't need to stop being a misogynist
asshole to have bought value and worth
please do but like to have value in
words yes like how do we still hear the
non-mechanical of all the misogynist
logic rejection is never required
because you never require attention
because you've never fallen right and so
redemption is never yea and redemption
is irrelevant by it by that rationale
redemption doesn't exist there is no
possibility of redemption cuz you never
fall you never need it right because you
never because the tribe starts kicking
you out right
you're still ostracized you still have
the shame but if they're not willing to
take you back in until you admit you
were wholly wrong and you're growing
well wait maybe they are still a racist
uh we help them get to less racist
you're wholly wrong is it but if you are
to be redeemed certainly in the eyes of
others you have to see things through
the eyes of others and at least accept
their you you may not agree with it
right you have to at least accept that
their criticism is valid from their
perspective you say I mean that the very
minimum redemption has to begin there
but a recognition that you have harmed
you have whether or not you intended to
whether or not you agree that you've
harmed that you have been perceived to
have harmed you have to at least
acknowledge that you know what I mean if
you if you refuse to even do that I
don't assuming that we accept the
possibility of redemption that you can
fall to a point where you need redeeming
do you know what I mean but yeah there
has to be there has to be some kind of
change otherwise how how how is
Redemption possible Ari is to put back
where it was before right and so I I
don't see how without change you can be
put back to where you were before I
don't see that but I do like a lot of
the metrics in society for change aren't
really changed there apologize to your
sister because you hit her stop using
that word it's offensive as opposed to
when you use that word here is all of
the history right if they're not if
they're not cognitively or emotionally
able to like get to that point and there
isn't a way we have to get them there
like all of this like stop being racist
and like this anybody know how to stop
someone for being racist even if you
yourself want to be less racist what is
the process like telling people to stop
being is not the way because it doesn't
work and so accepting people where they
are and saying there might be beauty and
love there even if this there's this
shit there - because we're all fully
good and bad human beings there's like
something there that's like and I think
part of it is what Kira said before this
idea and the person right if you don't
agree with my idea you're fundamentally
disagreeing with me as a human being I
know I do that all the time and figuring
that piece out in group right figuring
it out in safe enough
groups which means if someone's being a
racist ousel quite frankly I don't want
to be in conversation with them but that
doesn't mean I should put it on that
nobody should be in conversation with
them right that all of Twitter should
stop I'm not even gonna talk to you on
Twitter if you talk to them right that's
a whole other level of falling away from
the tribe where it's not even that
you're ostracized from this group I'm an
officer sighs everyone who even thinks
about taking you in
right which is like someone's in pain
they're acting in a shitty shitty way
and we inflict more pain on them
that just doesn't solve anything and I
think taking a step back is how we solve
it what is the reason they're doing the
shitty thing and how can we love them
and it makes less shit happen in my
hypothesis Brent you had something um
yeah I was just gonna say that you know
this is awkwardly close to the idea of
like Christian forgiveness where like
you know Christians might just do the
thing whatever it may be and then ask
for forgiveness right that's their kind
of method of just continually letting
themselves off off the hook but the
other example I wanted to bring in
that's a little bit related like to the
David Brooks thing is there's this guy
Peter Dao and he's like a hardcore
Democrat operative and writer and in the
2016 election he was really championing
Hillary Clinton and over the years since
he's like experienced like a profound
reversal right where he realizes that
like like he was just you know he should
have supported Bernie more you know more
in a more committed way and and and not
like just defaulted to the establishment
camp and so like it's this complete
turnaround and change of a person and
back in 2016 everybody did hate this guy
they completely you know tried to
ostracize him and and just because his
his tack was so centrist you know so
what it whatever it was it was just so
off-putting to the progressive left but
who he is
now today it's like on Twitter he's
constantly unpacking like how he was
wrong and what he learned in a way that
like you're kind of helping other people
understand what it what it means to
change in such a profound way and what
and what it takes to recognize that you
were wrong like it's such like I said at
the beginning like it's so rare but I
feel when you see it it's so powerful
and there's so many people who like you
you just see how intransigent they are
they just don't want to change and it's
like whether it's their personal belief
or they're just you know touting some
political line it's just so mainstream
that people don't change and we're in
this time of great change and flux and
upheaval and they're you know there has
to be convergence on new attractors the
the thing that you said about seeing
people that they don't want to change
that's actually something I've been
deeply reflecting on because there's
there are times when I have been accused
of being stuck that I'm not that I'm not
changing when in the reality is there is
constant change happening it just may
not be happening at this rate and speed
with which the people in my life want to
see it happen and there is no and in
there is a certain amount and you know
again right now I'm kind of like I've
never used religious words and yet they
seem to be coming up that there's the
grace of yeah it might take me a lot
longer to make the transition because I
have to let you know I have to let go of
this part of my identity and that part
of my identity many different pieces of
myself in order to come to that app in
you know come to that opinion or be able
to see things from your perspective
there is this underlying assumption that
because someone isn't willing to
acknowledge right now in this moment
that they are wrong that there isn't
some change happening every conversation
chain with people every you know it it
may not people may dig in and not be and
not change because there's a lot of
things like if I give up this opinion
will I be rejected by my entire family
that I you know deeply loved if I change
if I change this and admit I am wrong
does that mean that I am NOT this person
and there's all of these very complex
things that we make this a so when we
make this assumption that people don't
want to change I think that's a that's a
false premise to start with because
everyone in every interaction in every
moment is changing the and you know
there's this yeah I don't know and there
was the earlier Brent you said something
about you know a something for being
able to call out and call in and I think
and part of that is people being able to
take ownership for their responsibility
their their internal responses to
something that someone else said you
said something racist or sexist or
shitty or whatever and or I can say that
thing that you said brought up a ton of
emotion in me and not identify it as one
way or the other because and I may be
able to very clearly see that it's
racist and sexist but if I can bring up
to the surface that thing that you said
you know brought up these emotions and
here's what I you know here's what I
heard you say because it and and it
might be because if I just say clearly
that that's what you said was racist and
sexist if I repeat what I heard them say
maybe that was not at all what they
intended and maybe and so it's you know
it's a it's a very complicated piece of
this and I guess when I was thinking
about the redemption part of my journey
has been coming to a place of that I am
um you know Eric what you were talking
about that of that you know that there
is no falling you know I I
to come to a place of accepting that
there was something redeemable about me
because I came into you know my journey
with a deep sense of self hatred of I
was a despicable human being who did not
deserve life and that was and so I was
suicidal all of the time and so coming
to a place of that I am renewable gave
me had me come to a place to recognize
that everyone is redeemable because if I
am then everybody else's and to come to
that place and be able to acknowledge
that you know that there that that sense
of redemption has to is something that
has to both eat from inside but
sometimes you need it from the outside
before you can believe it from the
inside and and how do we create
environments where people get that
because somebody might come to the
conversation as a racist sexist asshole
and leave in their hearts that they are
irredeemable and to be so if I that to
be racist and sexist is to be redeemable
and but getting them from where they are
to kind of a place where they can hear
that might take a lot of building up of
their own internal resources all right
talk a lot Thank You Kira we are at the
masking our I'm just have this
conversation ten minutes ago end it but
I do want to interrupt you because it
was awesome
would everyone like to give a quick 30
second minute clothes and then we'll say
goodbye to YouTube
I'll go first because I do have to hop
off this was an amazing conversation and
I really appreciate it I love everything
that everybody brought and I love how
animated it was and I'm just so glad
that I got to participate thank you
Thank You Terra Preta Erick want to give
a closing statement really got nothing
that feels like it needs saying so no
yeah pass all right awesome thank you
this is also I loved this conversation
as well I'm up all the game be
conversations I saw
say thank you to human for participating
in the in the comments and saying some
cool things this idea Cafe is not really
we don't really interact with with the
watching audience it's just an
interaction between the four of us I
don't know if you guys can even see it
on this side I can't see if you click on
live comments you can say oh yeah and
we'll still be able to see them by
YouTube we're taking a break next week
I'll be back in January for a game B
conversation again who knows what we're
talking about we'll figure that out
later